

Teija Alasalmi - CV

Email: <u>teija.alasalmi@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/teija-alasalmi
Github: https://github.com/teijatestaaja/

I am a strong testing and test automation professional and an excellent team player. I have been working in software development in various roles since 2005. I have experience in the following industries: pension insurance, financial systems, public administration (Tax, Customs), education, translation, software localization, mobile networks and mobile games. I am fluent in Robot Framework, Python, JavaScript, Java and Kotlin. I enjoy new challenges both at work and in my spare time. My descriptive personality traits include perseverance, curiosity and willingness to experiment. I am a quick learner and I enjoy working in a team to achieve common goals for enabling customers' success.

Work Experience

Test Automation Specialist

10/2021 -

Tieto Finland Oy, Helsinki

Test Automation Developer

4/2021 - 9/2021

Gofore, Helsinki

Senior Test Automation Specialist /

Test Manager

1/2020 - 3/2021

CGI. Helsinki

Test Automation Specialist /

Test Manager / Test Consultant /

Test Engineer

6/2010 - 12/2019

Digia, Helsinki

Software Analyst

9/2008 – 5/2010

University of Jyväskylä

Mobile Game Tester

10/2005 - 8/2007

Digital Chocolate Inc., Helsinki

Project Coordinator

6/2005 - 9/2005

Suomen kieltenopettajien liitto, Helsinki

English Teacher

1/2005 - 6/2005

Lauttasaari Primary School, City of

Helsinki

Education

Master of Science

2020

Computer Science, Mathematics

University of Jyväskylä

Bachelor of Business IT

2021

Computer Programming

Haaga-Helia University of Applied

Sciences

Master of Arts

2014

English, Intercultural Studies

University of Jyväskylä

Bachelor of Science

2013

Computer Science, Pedagogical Studies for

Teachers, University of Jyväskylä

Bachelor of Arts

2011

English, Spanish, Language Technology

University of Jyväskylä

Finnish Matriculation Examination

1998

Specialized in Art, Mathematics and

Languages

Linnan lukio, Kajaani

Certifications

Scrum Master	ISTQB Test	ISTQB Certified	Language
Scrum Alliance	Manager	Tester	Certificate
2/2019	Advanced Level	Foundation Level	Spanish,
	9/2017	9/2013	Intermediate level

11/2011

Core Testing & Programming Skills

Test automation	Manual testing	Python (excellent)	C++, C (good)
Test planning	Acceptance testing	JavaScript (good)	HTML5 (good)
Test management	TDD, ATDD	Java (good)	XML (good)
Functional testing	Exploratory testing	Kotlin (good)	CSS (good)
Test case creation	API testing	React (good)	SQL, R (good)

Knowledge of Testing Tools, IDEs & Operating Systems

Azure DevOps	Robot Framework	Xcode	Android Studio
JIRA & Xray, Zephyr	Selenium + IDE	Visual Studio Code	Gimp
Quality Center	Detox	Eclipse	Photoshop
TestRail	Jest & Mocha	Visual Studio	Office Tools
TFS	SoapUI	Git, GitHub	Windows
Test Track Pro	OWASP ZAP	GitLab + Bitbucket	Mac OS, iOS
SpriraTest	DbVisualizer	Sublime Text	Linux basics
Bugzilla	SQLiteStudio	Postman	Android basics

Language Skills

Swedish (intermediate) Finnish (native)

English (working knowledge) French (basics) Spanish (working knowledge) Italian (basics)

Portuguese (intermediate) German, Japanese (very basics)

Hobbies

Rugby (Finland women's national rugby Coding & learning languages team 2008-2022, club rugby since 2008)

Shotokan karate (brown belt) Taekwondo (yellow belt)

Weight training

Crocheting & knitting

Video & mobile games, board games